(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone and
welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- My name is Katherine and
today we're bringing you another
elementary level lesson as
a part of our interview series.
- That's right, this is part
two of the interview series
and last part we talked
about, well, a brief
introduction when you
arrive to a job interview,
but on this occasion we're gonna talk
a little bit about yourself and your life.
- That's right, so this is the most
personal part, I think, of an interview.
Let's take a listen to today's
dialogue and we'll be back
in a moment to talk more about
the things that you've heard.
(upbeat music)
- Now, this child's
passed on your resume
to me and I've had a
chance to look it over.
I must say, I'm quite impressed.
- Thank you very much.
I've tried to keep it short and clear.
If there are any questions,
please feel free to ask me.
- Well, yes, I do have
a number of questions,
but perhaps first you could
give me a brief overview.
I'd like to get a little bit of
an idea of your background.
- Yes, of course.
Well, as you can see from the resume,
I'm 27 and grew up in Brooklyn, New York.
Although our family moved to London
when I was quite young, at around 16.
- Ah, I see, so you were
actually educated in Europe.
- Yes, precisely.
Although I was born in the US, I
would definitely call London Home,
but as you see, I've actually spent a lot
of my life moving from country to country.
My father was in the oil
business before he retired,
so we also spent a number
of years in Saudi Arabia too.
- Very interesting.
So seems you had quite
an adventurous childhood.
- Absolutely.
We were never still for too long, but
now I'm really looking to settle down.
- I see.
Okay, well, let's move on to
discuss your education, shall we?
- Sure.
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back.
So obviously, this person
had a very interesting life
and they used some pretty
interesting words there.
So why don't we take
a look at five key words
that we have prepared for
you on language takeaway?
- Language takeaway.
- All right, so the first word that we have
is right when Mr. Parsons
talked to Miss Childs
and he said that he was very
impressed with her resume.
- All right, so someone says I'm impressed
when they think that something that you did
or something about you is very interesting
or good or better than most people's.
- That's right, so you're kind of amazed,
you're kind of, you're like, wow, right?
And so this is an adjective I am impressed.
- That's right, so teachers
sometimes say this.
Maybe when you do
really, really, really well on a
test, they say, hey,
Marco, I'm really impressed.
You got 99%.
Parents say this to friends, family.
So basically, this is a
way to say good job, wow.
- Right, and there's also a verb.
So this is the adjective to be impressed
and the verb form would
be to impress someone.
So that's obviously, if
you impress your teacher
by studying, your
teacher will be impressed.
- That's right, and following that,
Mr. Person has some questions about Ms.
Child's background.
- That's right, he asked her for a
brief overview of her background.
So we have two interesting words there.
An overview, what is an overview?
- An overview is like a summary.
It's basically a way to ask for someone
to give you a lot of
information in very few words.
- That's right, so you don't
really want too much details.
You don't want somebody
to tell you their life in detail.
You just want to brief summary.
- Right, so not, I was born
on August 11th in 1979
and then I went into this and
no, this is basic, simple, this
is where I'm from, this is where
I went to school at the end.
- And well, he wanted a brief
overview of her background.
What exactly is her background?
- Well, think about the word back, okay?
That means behind.
Or in this case, background
is your personal history.
So you could ask someone,
what's your background?
It means where you from or, you know,
what have you been
doing up to now in your life?
- That's right.
And precisely when he asked
her about her background,
now she's starting
to talk about her life.
In general terms, as
we said, it's an overview.
So she said that she's 27 and
she's from Brooklyn, et cetera.
So she starts giving very general
information about herself and her life.
- Exactly, so when she starts to do this,
Mr. Person has more
specific questions about
her life because he
wants to know details.
So he asks her then where she was educated.
So this phrase, to be
educated is very important.
- That's right, so he's asking
her, you studied in Europe.
- That's right, to be educated means
to have someone teach you
or to go to school somewhere.
So for example, I was educated in America.
Where were you educated, Marco?
- I was educated in Chile.
- Wow, so you've been educated in a number
of different places, right, at
home and in a different country.
- Right, but you can also
specify the university name, right?
For example, I was educated at Harvard.
Can you say that?
- You can.
- Or I was educated at a
number of different schools.
- So you can say, I
studied or I was educated.
- All right, and well, apparently she was
moving around from Europe, United States.
So Mr. Person says, wow, it seems
that you had an adventurous childhood.
- Okay, this is a great
adjective, adventurous.
You can say, a person is adventurous.
So Marco is very adventurous.
He likes to jump out of airplanes,
but you can also say
that an experience is
adventurous like moving
around a lot as a child.
- Right, so I guess adventurous
can go hand in hand
with exciting or very
interesting full of emotions.
- That's right.
- Okay.
- Adventure, adventurous.
So a person can be adventurous
and we actually had a lesson
about this when we describe personalities.
You can say, someone is adventurous.
- Exactly.
- All right, very good.
So five key words that
we just took a look at.
Why don't we go back,
listen to the dialogue again,
and we'll be back to talk a
little bit more on Fluency Builder.
(upbeat music)
- Now, Ms. Child's passed on your resume to
me and I've had a chance to look it over.
- I must say, I'm quite impressed.
- Thank you very much.
I've tried to keep it short and clear.
If there are any questions,
please feel free to ask me.
- Well, yes, I do have
a number of questions,
but perhaps first you could
give me a brief overview.
I'd like to get a little bit of
an idea of your background.
- Yes, of course.
Well, as you can see from the resume,
I'm 27 and grew up in Brooklyn, New York.
Although our family moved to London
when I was quite young at around 16.
- Ah, I see, so you were
actually educated in Europe.
- Yes, precisely.
Although I was born in the US, I
would definitely call London home.
But as you see, I've actually spent a lot
of my life moving from country to country.
My father was in on the oil
business before he retired,
so we also spent a number
of years in Saudi Arabia too.
- Very interesting.
So seems you had quite
an adventurous childhood.
- Absolutely, we were
never still for too long,
but now I'm really
looking to settle down.
- I see.
Okay, well, let's move on to
discuss your education, shall we?
- Sure.
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back.
So we have four phrases
for you on fluency builder
prepared and let's start
on with the first one.
- Fluency builder.
Okay, so the very beginning, Mr.
Parsons, is continuing what
he was saying in our first part.
So Mr. Parsons is talking about Rebecca's
resume and he says,
"Someone, the secretary,
"she passed it on to me.
" So this verb, "to pass on.
" This is really important,
what does this mean?
- Well, the secretary, Ms.
Child's passed on Rebecca's resume.
That basically means she, Ms. Child
received it and she didn't keep it.
She passed it on or she gave it to
another person, in this case, Mr. Parsons.
- Okay, so this implies
the shows that something
doesn't stay with one
person, like you said, Marco,
but it moves from one
person to another person.
So for example, my mother
told me to pass this message
on to you, the message
is not for me, it's for you.
- I think also with physical traits, like
maybe if your mother had green eyes,
you can maybe say, "My mom
passed on her eye color on to me."
- That's right.
- So you got it from her.
- All right, so that's what
happened with the resume
and he said, "Well, she passed it on
"and I've had the chance to look it over.
" - Okay, so think about this as a chunk,
as a group of words that we use together,
to look something over,
we can say, "Hey, Marco,
"when you have a minute,
can you look this over for me?
" - Okay, so that means to
examine or to take a look.
- Take a look at, that's right.
So to look something
over or to look it over.
- All right, so basically to examine,
maybe in close detail, right?
You actually take the time to read it.
- That's right.
- Okay, and then later
on, they started talking
about her background, as we
know, she was from Brooklyn,
she grew up in Brooklyn, and
then she moved to London.
And so Rebecca described
how she spent most
of her life moving
from country to country.
- Okay, from country to country.
This means that she moved to
many different countries, okay?
So if I live in America all my life, I
never moved from country to country.
You can say this about many different things,
from place to place, from town to town.
It means that you go
from one place to another.
- That's right, so as you said, if
you replace the noun country,
you can say from town to town,
you can even say from house to house,
I went from house to
house asking for money.
- That's right, so from, to, - Exactly,
so from something to something.
And for our final phrase, she
was talking about how she's
moved around so much, that
she's actually ready to settle down.
- Okay, to settle down, this
is a really important phrase,
and I think it's something a lot of people
do when they're maybe in their 30s or 40s.
They don't want to move anymore.
So to settle down means
to stay in one place.
- Exactly, so you stay in one place.
- And it can have a lot of different meanings
as well, for example, to get married.
Many people say that's settling down,
it means you want to stay in
one place and have a family.
- Or to buy a house, because it means
that you will live there for a long time.
- Exactly, so to settle down.
So a lot of interesting
phrases there, a lot of words,
and this is, as we said,
part two of our series.
So I think it would be worthy for us
to listen to this dialogue one last time,
and we'll be back to
talk a little bit more.
(upbeat music)
- Now, Ms. Child's
passed on your resume to
me, and I've had a
chance to look it over.
I must say, I'm quite impressed.
- Thank you very much.
I've tried to keep it short and clear.
If there are any questions,
please feel free to ask me.
- Well, yes, I do have
a number of questions,
but perhaps first you could
give me a brief overview.
I'd like to get a little bit of
an idea of your background.
- Yes, of course.
Well, as you can see from the resume,
I'm 27, and grew up in Brooklyn, New York.
Although our family moved to London
when I was quite young, at around 16.
- Ah, I see, so you were
actually educated in Europe.
- Yes, precisely.
Although I was born in the US, I
would definitely call London home.
But as you see, I've actually spent a lot
of my life moving from country to country.
My father was in the oil
business before he retired,
so we also spent a number
of years in Saudi Arabia too.
- Very interesting.
So seems you had quite
an adventurous childhood.
- Absolutely.
We were never still for too long, but
now I'm really looking to settle down.
- I see, okay.
Well, let's move on to discuss
your education, shall we?
- Sure.
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back, so this is part
two of a 10-part series of interviews.
Now, we just talked about the
background and I think there
are different ways of talking
about your background, right?
This is maybe your personal background.
- That's right, so you can talk
about your personal history,
your personal background,
where you were born,
where you were educated,
where you grew up.
But a lot of times, we also have to
talk about other parts of our background,
like our work background, or like
next week, our educational background.
- That's right, so part three, we're gonna
take a look at your educational background
and it's gonna be very important
because I think in many interviews,
people have a hard
time describing what they
studied or maybe describing
exactly what they did
during university or college or
master's degree or something.
- Exactly, and we're not
talking about elementary school
or high school, we're specifically
talking about university background here.
So like you're saying,
Marco, what was your major?
What was your minor?
What was your area of studies?
These are great, great, great phrases
that are very important for an interview.
And so we hope that if you have
any questions, you'll let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com and
stay tuned for next week's episode.
- That's right, okay, so we'll see everyone
on the website and until next time.
- Bye. - Bye.
(upbeat music)